Realistically we can make data tell any story that we
事实上 我们可以让数据讲任何故事
want and you can twist the metrics to make anything sound like a win.
只要对指标做些处理 就能让数据看起来对我们有利
This is why it's really important that what you measure and report on is
这就是为什么你衡量和汇报的东西要有价值、有意义 是符合目标的
meaningful and that you're working on a shared vision for what you're trying to achieve.
而且你设定的目标要得到大家的共同认可
By staying on a shared vision,
朝着一个有共识性的目标前进
you'll avoid the mistake of crafting
可以避免对数据随意解释
a narrative that isn't true to what you're actually working towards.
从而偏离你的方向
Now as you're coming to see,
接下来
we continue to keep layering concepts together.
我们会继续将各种概念都组合到一起
We talked about creating smart objectives but it's time to start
之前我们讲了目标的 SMART 原则 现在是时候将所讲的
putting all of these layers together using a measurement framework.
各个层次都纳入一个衡量框架里
A measurement framework builds from the metrics up to your objectives.
一个衡量框架可以让你实现从指标到目标的建构
This is helpful, as you begin to work together
框架很重要 特别是你刚开始和
with other teams or even within your own team,
其他部门合作 或者在本部门内部合作
you can coordinate across all of the channels,
有助于你将各个渠道、平台、进行中的项目都
platforms, and initiatives that are underway.
整合起来
Additionally, if you go to work for a large company in a marketing department,
另外 如果你服务于一家大型企业的市场部门
you'll likely be introduced to an existing framework.
很有可能已经有了现成的框架
Companies use all sorts of frameworks to stay unified.
公司和企业都喜欢使用各种框架来保持统一性
Some companies are going to use smart objectives,
一些公司喜欢用 SMART 准则
others might use OKRs,
一些公司喜欢用 OKRs
which stand for Objective Key Results,
OKR 的全称是 Objective Key Results 目标及关键结果
and others might use a laddering framework that combines objectives with KPIs,
也有一些公司喜欢用阶梯式框架 将目标和 KPI 结合在一起
which stands for Key Performance Indicators.
KPI 全称是 Key Performance Indicators 关键绩效指标
Now, what's important is that you're aware that there is
你要记住
no one single framework but you
肯定不只有一个框架
really should be familiar that they exist and how to use them.
你应该知道有多个框架的存在 以及如何使用它们
Now, realistically, frameworks are just a helpful way
在实际工作里 框架可以帮助我们
of visualizing and making sense of data.
理解数据以及可视化数据
As you sit down and start out in the marketing analytics process,
当你真正开始市场分析流程的时候
you'll likely want to draft frameworks that help you.
你可能需要做一些框架初稿
But as you go about your day and day,
但是实际上
you're not really going to be drawing
你是不会为每一个可能碰到的问题
a frame work for every problem you're going to solve.
去做一个框架的
Now with that said, let's look at a very simple framework that helps you
所以 其实刚开始的时候 可以用一些简单的框架
start to connect the final dots between how all of this works together.
帮助你理解如何将前面讲的这些都融会贯通
Now, sometimes, we'll have a big picture framework,
比如 有时候会用 全局框架 (big picture framework)
starting at the top of the objectives,
最上面是目标 objective
followed by KPIs, and then metrics.
然后是 KPIs 最后是指标 metrics
So the top, we might substitute our smart goal for a fairly big picture objective.
所以在顶部 我们先把 smart 目标替换成一个比较大的全局目标
Let's say we've set a broad goal to simply create social media awareness.
假设我们的全局目标是提高社交媒体上的品牌知名度
Below this, we use our KPIs to summarize
在目标下面 我们用了 KPI 来代表
how well we are doing relative to those objectives.
与目标相关的一些预期成绩
Ultimately, this is the measurable and specific piece
这里就是对应 SMART 准则里的可衡量和具体性原则
of a smart goal but broken out for added clarity.
这样写更清晰一点
So we want to create awareness on social media.
所以我们是想提高品牌在社交媒体上的知名度
Then we might need to set our KPIs to measure against something,
那么我们的 KPI 怎么衡量呢？
and that could be reached in traffic.
可以用访客量和流量来衡量
Then we need to tie metrics to these.
然后我们使用相关的指标
These are the data points that inform our KPIs.
这些是组成 KPI 的关键数据点
So we'll need to measure impressions,
于是 我们可能会评估展现量、
engagements, and say unique visits.
用户与网站的互动 以及 访客量
Now, ultimately, this is really just a way to help
记住 框架可以帮助你想清楚自己要收集什么样的数据
plan for what data you're collecting and what you're measuring against.
以及用什么指标来衡量
I simply want you to always be thinking about
我希望你可以常常思考如何能将这些方面的内容
the layered approach and how this all stacks together.
整合在一起
Whether you have one objective or a dozen,
不管你有 1 个目标还是 100 个目标
or you use smart goals or broad goals combined with KPIs,
不管你用的是 SMART 原则还是 原则 + KPI 的方式 00:03:07,030 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 基本内容都是一样的 而且背后都应该要有一个框架来支撑